Okay, and let's headit.  Okay,
let's headit.  We are in
intermodular project 2 and the objective in
intermodular project 2, we will see in DAM 2
Dam Dam 25 26 second
intermodular project.  So it's good to continue
the introduction, right?  Continue with the
analysis.
The other day we were working on
aspects that make application design easier or more difficult
.  Okay.  And
well, let's go to Hey, no, not this.  This
is wrong.
This is wrong.  Okay.  Okay.  Yes, but no.
Okay,
prioritization of Okay, this has to go
in eh 001 basic contents
101 exercises
and that's it.
This is 001 basic contents
101 eh exercises.
Okay.  And now intervention planning
, okay?  001 basic contents
101 exercises.
Okay.  And now I'm going to
open
here in Dam, in second, in project, in
design.
Okay, this goes here,
this goes here.
Okay.  And we're going to start planning the
intervention and determining resources.
Let's see
in determining resources.   We are
closing.
Okay, let's get to this part.  Uh, 001
basic contents and 101
exercises.
Okay, I need to determine
the resources.  Let's talk about
material resources 001
introduction.md.
What kind of resources are they?  Well,
material resources,
economic resources
and
human resources.  What is a material resource?
Let's see.
Well, in my case, we
could separate the material resources into resources
needed
during development, that is, the prototype phase,
and resources needed
during implementation and
maintenance.
So, for example, this morning I
woke up, yesterday afternoon
we were working on the topic of the
east
of web sockets and this morning I
woke up and had a client saying,
"Hey, your application isn't working for me."
And I was like, "[ __ ], I've already ruined some of the
server."  Okay?  And then it
turns out I was connected to all of this,
I was going to class and I was in the car,
okay?, at 7:30 in the morning with the
computer on in the passenger seat.  I
mean, I was driving and at the same time
going into New York City to see what was happening,
okay?  And what basically happened,
what basically happened, mind you,
maybe they sent me a message, I don't
know before, but what
happened, uh, where is it?  I may have
deleted it, right?  Wait, here,
here.  Customer service.
2:35 a.m. mail.  your
SSL certificate has expired,
damn it.  So, thanks for letting me know 2.5
hours after the
certificate expires, okay?  So, of
course, first find out the error, the
certificate has expired, eh, then
fix it, get into os, renew the
certificate, download it, upload it to the
server.  All of this literally
while I was driving in the car, and
not as a co-pilot, but as if
driving at traffic lights.  I mean,
horrible, fatal.  Because?  Well, because
when you
implement an application and when you have
launched it, whether you like it or not, there is
maintenance, there are a series
of incidents, the server can
crash or the certificate can expire or
1000 other things can happen or it could be a one-off,
temporary failure or interruption
in the service by the provider, who
knows.  I mean, sometimes the solution
is, wait, this must be gold stuff,
wait 5 minutes, okay?  And that's it.  So
, well, I mean, just to
give you an example.  And I'm telling you, the
first thing I thought this morning was
that, I mean, I read the WhatsApp in
the elevator going down to the car and I
said, "There, yesterday we touched something on the
server and we messed it up."  Because I
said, it just so happens that yesterday
we touched something on the server and this
morning it doesn't work.  Okay, but it had
nothing to do with it, it was the certificate.  It could have
been that we had crashed the
server.  No problem,
I was just going in to open the virtual host and
delete everything we did
yesterday.  But well, then, what
resources?  Well, wait, what
human resources are needed?  Well, that
's the most complex part.  I'm going to start from a
supposed
24-hour support and in a
computer application it
is 24 hours a day,
meaning three
8-hour shifts, three rotating shifts or
whatever you want to call it.  So what I'm
asking you right now, so you can see
the importance of
determining resources, is, uh, how much
could a person dedicated
to maintenance earn?  That is, a
programmer who might not do anything
all day, but has to
be on call, that is, on 8-
hour shifts, and if something happens, he has to
fix it.  Tell me.  You can be at
home working, I mean, I don't
need exclusivity, okay?  You can
have another job, you can be a
freelancer, okay?  It's just that he
's on the lookout and if something happens during
his 8-hour shift, he can come in
and fix it and provide support or
whatever, okay?  What would you tell me?  I
want to tell you that it doesn't have to be
full-time, 8 hours of work,
okay?  How much could a person
with that parameter earn?  What are you telling me?
Let's see that I have the chat covered.
10000. I don't know.  Okay, let's put
10,000,
supposedly, 10,000
€ a month, okay?  €100 per month.  If we
are talking about three shifts, three
people, it means three people
earning €100 a month equals 10,000*
3, which equals €3,600 a month to
pay those three people, which
if you want we can multiply by 12,
okay?  Well, I come here with a
calculator,
okay?  and eh 3600*
12 is 43,000
multiplied by 12 months is 43,200
€ per year,
just in salaries, okay?  Only
in salaries.  Mind you, net.  For a
person to
earn €10,000 a month, you as a company
pay around €1,570, I
think, more or less.  Pilar Ruiz
can explain this better to us by month, because there is
one thing that is the net and another thing that
is the gross, so that's
43,000
out of 43,200
we can get to around
€52,000 more or less gross, okay?  You'd have to
consult the contribution tables for
each salary scale and all that.
What's going on?  Maybe you propose a
project to me and I'll say, okay,
you have €52,000 to spend on
salaries in a year.  Or
rather, justify to me that your project
will have an
income of at least €52,000 in the first year. I'm not saying it's enough
to make money, I'm saying it's enough to at
least be able to pay your employees.
Pay attention to what we're talking about,
okay?  But let's continue.  We have,
for example, a case, okay, of
human resources.
And now we discuss these numbers later,
okay?  Now then we talk about two
numbers, okay?  Eh, assuming
material resources,
let's say you develop it
at home, okay?  Okay.  How much would
the computer on which you
would develop that project cost?  I know what
you'll tell me, every year
the students tell me the same thing.  Okay?
You might say, "No, but I
develop it on my computer, I already
have it."  And I say, "Okay, imagine
if that computer breaks down."  Or
imagine you hire someone to work as a
programmer at a company and you have to
buy them a computer.  So
how much would that computer cost on which
the application could be developed?  that you are going
to create as a
business application.  Tell me, tell me something.
What do you say?
Around 1000, okay?  Around
€1,000 is a piece of computer equipment
that will be used for
development, implementation, and start-
up, okay?  and then
maintenance can also be done
from that computer.  So, uh, 1000
IT equipment for uh development,
implementation,
uh commissioning
and maintenance.
Clear.  Uh, one team
for the developer
and then another team
for the support team.  Let's say it
would be a team that would be in the
office, by the way, office,
we'll talk about it later, okay?  And let's say, every
8-hour shift, someone would come in,
sit down at their computer,
and do the work, and that's it.
So it's €2000. Okay,
sure, you do it at home, but if there's
a support team, well, I don't know, an
office.  Okay, let's assume an
office.  Supposed to rent an
office, an office, I mean, a
room, you know?  We're not going to rent out
an entire floor of Trump Tower.
But how much could an office rental cost
?
Okay.  Yes. Well, or a coworking space, Luis,
I mean, that's precisely what
this is for, in fact, I know people
who do that, you know?  What's more,
apart from coffee shops, which are
the best supermarket coffee shops lately, there are
people who arrive there, get a coffee, and
spend half the morning there working in the
cafeteria.  Okay, what's up.  Hello,
tell me.
Yeah, yeah,
okay, wait a minute, guys, give me a
second.
This over here and I'll stop too.